rhapsody.com 2012-12-21

# Rhapsody Privacy Policy

Rhapsody International Inc. ("RI") is committed to protecting the privacy of your Personal Information (defined below). This Privacy Policy explains how RI collects and utilizes Personal Information to enhance your Rhapsody experience during your use of Rhapsody products and services. 

RI collects Personal Information to improve the manner by which RI operates and offers its products and services, communicates with you about those products and services, and provides effective, timely customer support when needed. RI does not intentionally collect Personal Information from users under 13 years of age. RI will not rent, sell, or distribute any Personal Information without your consent, unless such sharing is necessary for the purposes set forth in this Privacy Policy. RI understands that it is a privilege to have you as a customer and uses reasonable measures to safeguard your personal information. 

To access or download any of RI's products and services, including free trials, you must open an account via RI's online or mobile registration process. Information gathered during the registration process or when you access Rhapsody products and services, including the Rhapsody Social Network, may differ based on the nature of the product or service and may include: name and email address, billing information, information concerning software downloaded, products and content purchased, accessed, downloaded and/or burned through RI products or services (including, in the case of music products, tracks streamed, purchased or saved in libraries or playlists), location information (such as zip code or postal code and country), computer configuration (such as operating system, connection speed, and peripherals), the IP Internet (IP) address and URL of the website that sent you to the RI registration page, the types of peripherals (including portable media players) used by RI products on your computer (to ensure that you have access to the latest fixes and patches for full compatibility with these devices), your device's Unique Device Identifier (UDID), geographic location, demographic information provided by you (such as language, gender and age, and, if applicable, content preferences and personalization information), and whether you logged into or out of an RI service, or changed your password or billing information (collectively, "Personal Information"). 

RI uses your Personal Information to: 

  * Deliver to you and bill you for RI products and services, and communicate with you concerning your account and customer service issues. This may include verifying authorization of credit card usage before any purchase of premium content or services (e.g., for the purposes of access to a free trial, or to the Music Store);
  * Verify access rights to premium content or other access-restricted services and software, including for the purpose of supporting digital rights management software;
  * Improve our software and services by providing personalized content recommendations, language and location customization, and/or personalized help and instructions; 
  * Determine if you meet the minimum system requirements to use our products, and provide information concerning compatibility and interoperability to you; 
  * Track content accesses, downloads and burns for the purpose of paying royalties and license fees to third party providers, such as record labels and other copyright holders and content distributors; 
  * Track registration traffic for purposes of paying advertising partners;
  * Ask you to participate in surveys about products, services, news and events; 
  * Offer you product upgrades, content, services and games for you to purchase; 
  * Create your non-personally-identifiable Rhapsody Social Network profile;
  * Provide you with content, services, instructions, and a more personalized experience based on non-sensitive Personal Information, such as your language preferences, zip/postal code, country locations, and any content or other preferences you provide; 
  * Auto-update downloaded RI products;
  * Provide you with news, free newsletters, updates, targeted advertising, promotions, and special offers; and 
  * Better understand how our products are used, including Web and mobile traffic patterns and what types of content are most popular with users of our products and services;
  * Test and develop upgrades and improvements to our products and services.

RI does not use your Personal Information for purposes incompatible with those listed above. 

In some cases, access to certain products and services, such as content subscription products, the RI Social Network, or products distributed by third parties may require the provision of Personal Information to a third party, such as a content provider, email provider, social media site, advertising network, or distributor. This Privacy Policy does not limit RI's ability to share aggregated or anonymized Personal Information with such third party partners and affiliates. RI may also receive your Personal Information from third party service partners and advertisers in an effort to facilitate personalization of your content preferences. The third party's use of such information is governed by that party's privacy policy, and RI's use is governed by this privacy policy. Please visit the privacy policy of the content partner to make sure you understand how they use the personal information you provide to them. If you do not wish for such a transfer to take place, you should not register for the applicable product or service. You may also choose to control your privacy settings using the [NAI opt-out tool](http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp) which allows consumers to opt out of the behavioral advertising delivered by NAI member companies as explained below in the section regarding Cookie usage. Additionally, RI may be required to provide specific access and usage information to certain content providers and rights holders as a condition of content licensing. In such cases, RI may provide content usage, access, demographic and other information without your personally identifiable information (your name, billing information, email address) to the content provider. RI is not responsible for nor does it assume liability for any third party's use of Personal Information in violation of its own privacy policy or applicable law. 

RI may disclose relevant information about its customers to our contractors (e.g. a customer service contractor or a credit card clearing service) in order for them to provide specific services for RI to better serve our customers. RI's contractors are bound by contractual requirements to keep the information they process secure. 

If RI merges with, is acquired by, or transfers ownership to another entity, RI may share your Personal Information with that entity. Any such disclosures will remain protected by the then-current Privacy Policy. In the event that RI files for bankruptcy RI will not sell any Personal Information or user data so long as the Rhapsody service is terminated as a result of the bankruptcy. 

Also, RI may disclose your Personal Information if required to do so by law or in the good faith belief that such action is necessary to: (a) conform to the edicts of the law; (b) comply with the order of a competent judicial authority in any jurisdiction; (c) comply with legal process served on RI; (d) protect and defend the rights or property of RI; or (e) act in urgent circumstances to protect the personal safety of users of RI products or the public at large. 

Your credit card will be charged for the renewal term of your Service on your billing date ("Billing Date"), based on the type of subscription (e.g., on a particular date each month for a monthly subscription; on the three-month date for a quarterly subscription; on the anniversary for an annual subscription, etc.). If, however, your Activation Date is on the 29th, 30th or 31st day of a month, and your Billing Date does not exist in a particular month because there are fewer than thirty-one (31) days in the month payment is due, your Billing Date for that particular renewal will be on the last day of the month in which your Billing Date would otherwise be. 

RI websites and products contain links to other websites and products. RI is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of such websites or products. Please visit the privacy policies of these third party sites in order to understand their privacy policies and data collection practices. 

##  Obligatory or Optional Nature of the Requested Information 

Some of the Personal Information collected by RI is necessary to provide you with the RI product or service you choose and to optimize the delivery of audio and video data to your computer. RI software may include the opportunity to disable certain software features to increase your level of privacy. However, certain technical information (e.g., zip code, product id, GUID) may be automatically transmitted between networked servers to authenticate access to products and services, enable their delivery, or optimize your media delivery experience. 

Registering for a product or service allows you to tell us how or whether you want RI to communicate with you. Generally, RI sends e-mail about its products, content and special offers. You may opt out of receiving RI marketing e-mails and/or newsletters by clicking the "unsubscribe" link at the bottom of any email you receive from Rhapsody. Additionally, your online RI account, accessed through the "My Account" link provided in emails and on RI Web pages, enables you to select whether you wish to receive newsletters, marketing, promotional emails, and special offers. However, RI may continue to send you e-mail about products or services you have previously purchased (such as an available upgrade that you are entitled to receive), your account status or other information concerning functions, features and status of your RI products and services, or to inform you about critical technical service issues relating to a RI product or service. 

To access your account information and preferences, select "Manage My Account" from the menus on the RI software. Sign in to your account and modify your information and preferences as needed. 

You may also review and update your account on the web at [www.rhapsody.com](http://www.rhapsody.com/), by selecting "My Account," and logging in using your name and password. 

When you access your account by logging in, you can update and/or make sure that your account information is accurate. You can also manage your preferences concerning receipt of newsletters, promotional emails, and profile sharing settings. To Edit your Rhapsody Social Network profile sharing settings you must log in to your account at www.rhapsody.com; select the "My Music" menu; then click on "Profile". 

If you have forgotten a username or password, please refer to RI's online help resources. 

Cookies are pieces of text sent from a web server and retained by your web browser for purposes of storing site preferences. Flash cookies are functionally equivalent to browser cookies, but are managed via Adobe Flash's preferences, rather than the browser's preferences. Like other major websites, RI uses cookies and flash cookies to provide you with a tailored experience when visiting its websites and using its products. RI also uses cookies to understand traffic patterns on RI websites and to authorize access to certain premium or trial content and product features. RI treats any Personal Information that may be contained in cookies with the same level of confidentiality as other information you provide to RI. RI also works with online advertising companies who may use cookies and flash cookies to track your browsing preferences and provide targeted advertisements based upon those preferences. Some of these advertisers are members of the NAI (Network Advertising Initiative) which provides you the option to stop receiving targeted advertisements at the following link: <http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp>. Please note that using the NAI opt-out tool does not necessarily mean that you will no longer receive online advertising; instead, using the NAI opt-out tool means that advertisers who are members of the NAI organization will no longer deliver ads tailored to your web preferences and usage patterns. 

RI does not require that you accept cookies; however, some functionality on its websites, its product purchase check-out process, and products and services may be disabled if you decline to accept cookies. You can disable cookies within your browser or set your browser to notify you and give you the option to decide whether or not to accept each cookie you receive. To disable Flash cookies, you will need to turn them off in Adobe's Flash preferences by clicking [here](http://www.macromedia.com/support/documentation/en/flashplayer/help/settings_manager03.html). For information on browser cookie preferences please [click here](http://www.aboutcookies.org/Default.aspx?page=1#ie8x). You may also change your cookie settings through preferences options in our products. 

RI may revise this Privacy Policy as needed to keep it up to date with RI products, services and Web pages. "Updated" may be used to alert users to recent changes and to the date of the last update. RI also posts FAQs from time to time on specific products. 

The Personal Information practices set out in this Privacy Policy apply to all RI customers. 

If you are a European resident and your data privacy complaint was not satisfactorily addressed by RI, you may contact the Direct Marketing Association at: 

Safe Harbor Line   
Direct Marketing Association   
1111 19th Street, NW - Suite 1100   
Washington, DC 20036   
E-mail: safeharbor@the-dma.org   
Web: <http://www.the-dma.org/safeharbor/consumers.shtml>

RI customarily releases alpha and beta versions of our products, which are further refined before the release of the final version. Because these products are still in a test phase, RI may not always catch an unintended privacy issue, despite our efforts to do so. As such, RI welcomes feedback on any privacy concerns you may have, and on how to improve RI products generally, in all stages of release. RI does not guarantee error-free performance under this privacy policy. RI will use reasonable efforts to comply with this Privacy Policy and will take prompt corrective action when RI learns of any failure to comply with it. RI shall not be liable for any incidental, consequential or punitive damages relating to this Privacy Policy. 

If you have questions about the privacy aspects of our products or services or would like to make a complaint, please contact: 

Privacy Policy Group   
Rhapsody Legal Department   
500 3rd St #460   
San Francisco, CA 94107 

NOTE: Rhapsody is a trademark of RI 

Last modified: July 13, 2012
